usaa.com 2015-03-19

# Privacy | USAA

  * Tab 1  _Privacy_
  * Tab 2  _Personal Information_
  * Tab 3  _Online Practices_
  * Tab 4  _Privacy Preferences_

## Our Privacy Promise to You

By choosing USAA, you have expressed confidence in our ability to serve you. We take this responsibility seriously and we diligently safeguard your personal information.

  *  **We don't sell your information.** We share information outside of USAA only as permitted by law for our everyday business purposes.
  *  **Your information is confidential.** Our employees and the companies we contract with are obligated to hold member information in the strictest confidence.
  *  **We protect your information.** We have physical security on site, rigorous security procedures and world-class virus and intrusion detection software.

## No action is needed if you agree with our privacy practices

However, you can opt out to limit the information we share and use within the USAA family of companies:

  * View your [privacy preferences](https://www.usaa.com/inet/ent_securityprefs/SecurityPreferences?action=executetask&target=EditPrivacyPrefs) or
  * Call 1-800-531-7154 — our menu will prompt you through your choices.

## Your Personal Information and Identity

There are precautions you can take to help protect your personal information and your identity online.

### Don't Become a Victim of Identity Theft

Identity theft occurs when someone uses your name, Social Security number, credit card number or other personal information to purchase a product or service.

#### Signs You Could be a Victim

  * You're not getting your bills or other mail.
  * You see suspicious charges on your accounts.
  * You get a credit card you didn't apply for.
  * You're unexpectedly denied credit.
  * You get information about services and products you didn't buy.

### Protect Yourself Online

  *  **Keep a clean machine.** Having the latest security software, web browser and operating system are the best defenses against viruses, malware and other online threats for all your devices. Turn on automatic software updates if that's an available option.
  *  **Protect your personal information.** Make passwords long and strong, and create different passwords for each of your accounts. If you write down your passwords to remember them, make sure they are stored in a secure location away from your devices.
  *  **Connect with care.** Delete or mark as junk any suspicious links in email, tweets, posts and online advertising. If you don't know and trust the source, delete it. Limit the type of business you conduct in public Wi-Fi hotspots.
  *  **Be web wise.** Be wary of communications that ask you to act immediately or that ask you for personal information. Protect your valuable work, music, photos and other digital information by making an electronic copy and safely storing it.
  *  **Be a good online citizen.** Post only about others as you would have them post about you. Help the authorities fight cyber crime by reporting stolen finances or identities and other cybercrime to the Internet Crime Complaint Center at [www.ic3.gov](http://www.ic3.gov/ "Opens New Window"), and to your local law enforcement or state attorney general as appropriate.

You can find more information about these and other online safety habits from **[STOP. THINK. CONNECT. ™](http://www.stopthinkconnect.org/ "Opens New Window"),** the global cybersecurity awareness campaign launched in partnership with the U.S. government to help all digital citizens stay safer and more secure online.

### Use Social Media Wisely

Social media can connect you with family and friends, colleagues and businesses in an online community. However, just as in real-world communities, you should be careful what you share and how you share it.

#### Use Privacy Controls

Privacy controls allow you to restrict who can see your profile and posts. Options change frequently and you should check and update your settings often.

#### Watch What You Post

When posting, keep in mind that even a deleted post may have already been copied and the content may still be in the provider's system even if you can no longer see it. You also shouldn't post significant information about family members, such as their birthdays, ages or even their names.

#### Don't Reveal Too Much on the First Date

Personal information such as where you live, work or go to school could be used against you. Travel plans can give an indication that your home may be unoccupied. Identity thieves will read through your profile history which can paint a detailed picture of who you are.

#### How and Where to Post Photos

Photos taken with newer cameras and Smartphones can include your location embedded in the image. This can show criminals where you are even if you don't mention it in the post. The background of the photo may also give away information.

#### Phishing

Social media has seen an increase in phishing as people migrate away from email. Beware of links from friends or business users whose accounts you have not verified. These links could infect your computer with malicious software and put your information and online activity at risk.

### Practice Public Safety

When using a credit or debit card:

  *  **Only carry the identification, credit and debit cards that you need.**
  *  **See if the card reader appears to be damaged or modified.** If so, don't use it. Thieves sometimes use a tactic called skimming where they alter a machine to get a copy of your card information.
  *  **Be aware of people and surroundings.** Don't approach an ATM if you don't feel secure about its location or people around it. Protect your privacy by shielding the keypad with your hand or body while entering your PIN.
  *  **Stash your cash.** After completing your transaction, secure your card and cash immediately, before leaving the area. Count your cash later, in the safety of your home or locked car. Your card is like cash, so keep it in a safe place.
  *  **Keep your card in sight.** When completing a purchase in person, make sure you can see the cashier who takes your card whenever possible. If they leave the area and you feel uncomfortable, ask to speak to a manager. Make sure you check your statement and charges regularly, especially if you're worried about suspicious behavior.

#### Tell us about identity theft, lost cards   
or suspicious activity.

Report Fraud

## Questions?

Call **1-800-531-7154** and ask to speak to a representative.

## Online Information Practices

Protecting your personal and financial information is a responsibility USAA takes very seriously. This Online Information Practices Notice ("Notice") applies to usaa.com, USAA mobile applications, and other sites or consumer applications owned and operated by USAA. This Notice describes how we may collect and use your information. We will use and share any information that we collect from or about you in accordance with the [USAA Privacy Promise](https://www.usaa.com/inet/pages/privacy_promise) or the [European Privacy Statement](https://www.usaa.com/inet/pages/privacy_statement_europe), as applicable.

We gather information on usaa.com (through the use of cookies and information you submit) that helps us protect you, maintain the security of our website and for the purposes described below.

### Types of Information We Collect

The Types of Information USAA CollectsInformation Obtained| Purpose  
---|---  
  
 **Previous URL you visited**

| 

  * Site management
  * marketing

 **Transaction information you submitted on our site**

| 

  * Site management
  * Marketing
  * Complete transactions
  * Routine business purposes

 **Site navigation, pages you visited, time you spent on pages**

| 

  * Site management
  * Marketing

 **Polls, surveys on our site**

| 

  * Display survey results
  * Marketing

 **Postings on our site**

| 

  * Display postings
  * Respond to posting
  * Marketing

 **Marketing Cookies**

| 

  * Marketing

 **Device Identifiers**

| 

  * Security

 **Clicks on USAA ads and related pages**

| 

  * Marketing

 **Non-USAA Accounts**

| 

  * Display accounts
  * Personal financial management
  * Payment transactions
  * Marketing

 **Social Media information**

| 

  * Site Management
  * Marketing

 **Biometric information**

| 

  * Security
  * Authentication

 **Geolocation information**

| 

  * Security
  * Site management
  * Marketing

### How We Use Your Information

How USAA Uses Your Information

 **Security Purposes**

| 

  * Maintain a secure session.
  * Authenticate your computer.
  * Detect potentially fraudulent transactions.
  * Verify transactions.

---|---  
  
 **Site Management**

| 

  * Provide technical assistance.
  * Tailor the content we display to you on USAA.com.
  * Resolve performance issues with USAA websites.
  * Improve search engine placement.
  * Improve website navigation and page effectiveness.

 **Marketing**

| 

  * Offer solutions that match your interests and needs.
  * Follow up on transactions you initiate.
  * Tailor the advertising displayed to you on third-party sites.

### Social Media Information

USAA will use social media information so we can improve our member service and provide more personalized offers and experiences. If you give us permission, USAA will be able to collect only the information that is made publicly available based on your Facebook and Twitter privacy settings, not your social account password or any non-public information. To learn more about protecting your privacy and password, go to USAA's [Security Center](https://www.usaa.com/inet/pages/security_center "Opens New Window").

Each social network provides different types of information. Facebook may provide your username, likes, public posts, and other basic data, while Twitter may offer your username, tweets, and basic profile. You will be given a description of what may be collected when you use the tool to connect to USAA with your social account. All social media information will be protected in accordance with our [Privacy Promise](https://www.usaa.com/inet/pages/privacy_promise "Opens New Window").

### Third-Party Cookies

We contract with companies to distribute e-mails on USAA's behalf and to deliver online advertisements on usaa.com, on other websites and on other applications. These companies use third-party cookies, website scripting and a technology called an "Action Tag," to collect anonymous information about visitors to our sites (for example, to learn which online ads attracted visitors). These third-party cookies help us analyze our website and the effectiveness of our marketing. These cookies do not contain personally identifiable information about you.

### Third-Party Advertisers

Third parties, including our service providers, may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites, including when you visit our website. These companies may place anonymous cookies on your computer. These third-party cookies help us provide relevant marketing to you when you visit, or based on your activity on, our website or third-party websites. They do not contain personally identifiable information about you.

In providing interest-based ads, we follow the cross-industry Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance. To learn more about these third parties and your choices regarding their collection of information, visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ "Opens New Window") and <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>. Any opt out election you make is valid only for the computer/browser combination used to opt out. Even if you opt out, you may still receive advertisements from us, but they will not be customized based on your web-browsing activities. Clearing cookies will remove the opt out since it is stored in a cookie.

### Updates

We may periodically make changes to this Notice. If we make any changes, we will revise the date at the bottom of this Notice. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Notice on usaa.com. Your use of usaa.com, a USAA mobile application, or other sites or consumer applications owned and operated by USAA following these changes means that you accept the revised Notice.

 _Last updated June 10, 2014._

#### Tell us about identity theft, lost cards   
or suspicious activity.

Report Fraud

#### Questions?

Call **1-800-531-7154** and ask to speak to a representative.

## Your Privacy Preferences

No action is needed if you agree with our privacy practices. However, you can opt out to limit the information we share and use within the USAA family of companies.

#### Tell us about identity theft, lost cards   
or suspicious activity.

Report Fraud

#### Questions?

Call **1-800-531-7154** and ask to speak to a representative.
